<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-08-21T11:58:30-05:00</updated><id>/blog/feed.xml</id><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Seven Larson</name></author><entry><title type="html">devlog #1</title><link href="/blog/media/2023/08/21/devlog-01.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="devlog #1" /><published>2023-08-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-08-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/blog/media/2023/08/21/devlog-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/media/2023/08/21/devlog-01.html"><![CDATA[<p>today i finally sat down and started to learn how to use ink / inky. i figured if i want to even have a shot at entry-level narrative positions, i’d better have some public work to show off under my belt, so i’d better get cracking :)</p>

<p>i actually spent way more time figuring out how to make this blog than i spent messing with inky, because it turns out inky is really quick to get the hang of. the devlog was a last-second strike of inspiration.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>most of day 1 was coming up with my concept (one i’ve had for awhile, actually), and then starting to hash out the specifics of how structuring works. i actually started with twine, which was… well, it was fine. i always thought i was sort of a visual person, but it turns out, i’m a very language-oriented person.</p>

<p>who would have guessed!</p>

<p>and seeing the words laid out in front of me in an almost more code-like way like how ink and the inky editor function actually worked a lot better for me. it’s very similar to the html/css work i dabble in with brackets, so i felt right at home.</p>

<p>figuring out basic branching was pretty straight-forward. i also figured out how to add simple conditional statements (e.g. “this line only gets said if the player has seen this scene”) and a little dice roll.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/post_images/2023/august/21/inky_gettingstarted.png" alt="a screenshot of an inky work-in-progress" /></p>

<p>getting the live preview working was straight-forward also, at least by just exporting. i haven’t quite figured out how to get it to keep my CSS though. i can set classes in inky, but then i can’t define the CSS for those classes until after i export it for web…? and i can’t re-export into the same location apparently…? maybe i’m missing something. i can’t find a lot of info online about it. i could just copy the CSS file somewhere externally and then overwrite it after exporting every time i guess. what a pain!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/post_images/2023/august/21/inky_gettingstarted_preview.png" alt="a screenshot of the live preview of my ink test" /></p>

<p>maybe more soon! i thought about making videos but. it turns out narrative devlogs are just a lot of writing. a little boring maybe, lol.</p>]]></content><author><name>Seven Larson</name></author><category term="media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[today i finally sat down and started to learn how to use ink / inky. i figured if i want to even have a shot at entry-level narrative positions, i’d better have some public work to show off under my belt, so i’d better get cracking :) i actually spent way more time figuring out how to make this blog than i spent messing with inky, because it turns out inky is really quick to get the hang of. the devlog was a last-second strike of inspiration.]]></summary></entry></feed>